<resources>
    <string name="app_name">TourApp</string>
    <string name="txt_sr">Srirangam</string>
    <string name="txt_pul">Puliyancholai Falls</string>
    <string name="txt_nit">Kallanai Dam</string>
    <string name="txt_muk">Mukkombu</string>
    <string name="txt_rock">Rockfort</string>
    <string name="g_museum">Gandhi Museum</string>
    <string name="me_temple">Meenakshi Temple</string>
    <string name="th_mahal">Thiru Nayakkar Mahal</string>
    <string name="sa_hills">Samanar Hills</string>
    <string name="mk_falls">Monkey Falls</string>
    <string name="bla_thu">Black Thunder</string>
    <string name="sir_fall">Siruvani Falls</string>
    <string name="ko_fal">Kovai Kutralam</string>
    <string name="vel_hills">vellingiri Hills</string>
    <string name="matina">Marina Beach</string>
    <string name="san_chur">SanThome Church</string>
    <string name="conn_lib">Connemara Library</string>
    <string name="anna_zoo">Anna Zoological Park</string>
    <string name="puli_lak">Pulicat lake</string>
    <string name="mon_fall">Monkey Falls are natural waterfalls located near the uphill ghat road Valparai on the Pollachi-Valparai road in the Anaimalai Hills range, in Coimbatore district. Monkey Falls is about 30 km from Pollachi. Refreshing Natural Water Falls about 6 km from Azhiyar Dam. Monkey Falls is located on road connecting Pollachi and Valparai. The Monkey falls is an excellent roadside stop situated 65 kilometers (40 mi) from Coimbatore and 29 kilometers (18 mi) from Pollachi on the Coimbatore - Pollachi - Valparai main road next to Arutperunjothi Nagar and Azhiyar Valparai Forest Department Check Post of IFS. Monkey Falls is a famous and popular tourism spot. People ravelling in the area of Coimbatore or Pollachi will want to visit Monkey falls as it is an outstanding scenic attraction. Monkey falls is an ideal place for little children and adults to take a bath. Ticket fee is Rs 20 to enter inside the falls vicinity</string>
    <string name="str_bla">Black Thunder is a water theme park located in Tamil Nadu, India. It is situated at the foot of Nilgiris near Mettupalayam, in Coimbatore 40 km north of the city and occupies an area of about 75 acres (300,000 m2). The park offers about 49 rides, Surf Hill and the Wild River Ride notable among them. The park has a hotel situated within its premises. It charges (per Person In Rs.) Adult 690/-, Child(3 To 10 yrs) 590/-, School 390/-, College 490/-. It is owned by LA Group which also owns Jenney Club Residency on Avinashi Road, Coimbatore</string>
    <string name="str_siru">Siruvani Waterfalls and the dam named after them are located 35 km (22 mi) west of Coimbatore in the Western Ghats. The reservoir at Siruvani was built for Tamil Nadu by the Kerala government with funds collected by the Tamil Nadu government to meet the drinking water requirements of Coimbatore. The gateways on either side of the road across the dam are typical of the Kerala and Tamil architectural styles. Siruvani is also home to certain tribals like the Mudugars and Irulars. Water from Siruvani River is renowned for its taste and mineral properties, and the view from the falls and the dam is a tourist attraction.

The sweetness has been attributed to the vegetation and rocks through which the water flows in the Attapady area; however, later it was discovered that the sweetest water on earth is located in the state of Andhra Pradesh - Guntur district</string>
    <string name="str_kovai">Kovai Kutralam is a scenic spot with a gentle waterfall originating on the Siruvani hill ranges. It is located on the western ghat mountain range that lies to the west of this city at a distance of about 35 kms from Coimbatore. The siruvani dam is just above this water fall and this place is under the control of forest department. Permission has to be sought from them to visit this Kovai Kutralam Falls. Limited bus service is available from the city and this area is out of bounds after 5 pm. This is the only place near Coimbatore where you find a nice enchanting waterfall.</string>
    <string name="str_velli">The Velliangiri Mountains, (Tamil: வெள்ளியங்கிரி மலை) a part of the Nilgiri Biosphere Reserve, are situated at the Western Ghats border of Coimbatore district, Tamil Nadu. Known as the "Thenkailayam (Tamil: தென்கயிலை) - Kailash of the South", these mountains are held and revered on par with spiritually most powerful place on the planet - Mount Kailash, the legendary abode of Lord Shiva. On the top of the Velliangiri Mountains, Shiva is worshipped as Swayambhu, one who is self-created and in this form, he graces the devotees.

Besides, the Shiva Temple of Velliangiri, the presence of the Dhyanalinga is another reason why people throng to the Velliangiri Hills.</string>
    <string name="str_gmuseum">Gandhi Memorial Museum, established in 1959, is a memorial museum for Gandhi located in the city of Madurai in Tamil Nadu, India. Known as Gandhi Museum, it is now one of the five Gandhi Sanghralayas (Gandhi Museums) in the country. It includes a part of the blood-stained garment worn by Gandhi when he was assassinated by Nathuram Godse.\nLocated in a quiet place, it is a very good memorial of Gandhiji, it contains a "Visual Biography of Bapuji" containing photos, paintings, sculptures, manuscripts, quotations and some of the selected Photostat copies of many of letters written by him and some of his renderings. This section contains 124 rare photographs depicting various phases of Mahatma Gandhi right from his childhood days until being taken to the crematorium.</string>
    <string name="str_meena">Meenakshi Amman Temple is a historic Hindu temple located on the
    southern bank of the Vaigai River in the temple city of Madurai, Tamil Nadu, India. It is
    dedicated to Parvati, known as Meenakshi, and her consort, Shiva, here named Sundareswarar. The
    temple forms the heart and lifeline of the 2,500-year-old city of Madurai and is a
    significant symbol for the Tamil people, mentioned since antiquity in Tamil literature.\nIt houses 14 gopurams (gateway
    towers), ranging from 45–50m in height. The tallest is the southern tower, 51.9 metres (170 ft)
    high,and two golden sculptured vimanas, the shrines over the garbhagrihas (sanctums) of the
    main deities. The temple attracts 15,000 visitors a day, around 25,000 on Fridays,[8] and
    receives an annual revenue of ₹ 60 million.</string>
    <string name="str_tnayak">Thirumalai Nayak Palace is a 17th-century palace erected in 1636 AD by King Thirumalai Nayak, a king of Madurai\'s Nayaka dynasty who ruled Madurai from 1623–59, in the city of Madurai, India. This Palace is a classic fusion of Dravidian and Rajput styles. The building, which can be seen today, was the main Palace, in which the king lived.\n The original Palace Complex was four times bigger than the present structure.\n In its heyday, Tirumalai Nayak Palace at Madurai was considered to be one of the wonders of the South. This palace is situated 2 km south east of the Meenakshi Amman Temple.</string>
    <string name="str_sama">Samanar Hills or Samanar Malai is a hill rock complex located in Keelakuyilkudi village, 15 kilometres (9.3 mi) from Madurai, Tamil Nadu, India.The hill has been declared as a protected monument by the Archaeological Survey of India.\nSamanar means Jain in Tamil and malai means hill. This hill has caves where Tamil Jain (Samanar) monks lived.The hill was also known as Thiruvuruvagam.
Settipodavu.Samanar Malai has several Tamil-Brahmi inscriptions, a number of stone beds and many sculptures, which shows authority for Jainism in the ancient Tamil country.\nThe hill contains two famous sculptures, Settipodavu and Pechipallam, that show images of Jain Tirthankaras made by Jain monks in the 9th century BCE</string>
    <string name="str_puli">Pulicat Lake Bird Sanctuary is a famous 481 km² located in Nellore, Chittoor districts of Andhra Pradesh and Protected area in Thiruvallur District of Tamil Nadu state near Elavur in South India. Pulicat Lake is the second largest brackish-water eco-system in India after Chilka lake in Orissa.\nInternational name: Pulicat Lake Wildlife Sanctuary.\nPulicat Lake may disappear within 100 years by being filled up with silt.Government and private NGO efforts are working to halt lake destruction.</string>
    <string name="str_anna">Arignar Anna Zoological Park,also known as the Vandalur Zoo, is a zoological garden located in Vandalur, a suburb in the southwestern part of Chennai, Tamil Nadu, about 31 kilometres (19 mi) from the city centre and 15 kilometres (9.3 mi) from Chennai Airport. It previous location was set up in 1855 and was the first public zoo in India. It is affiliated with the Central Zoo Authority of India.Spread over an area of 602 hectares (1,490 acres), including a 92.45-hectare (228.4-acre) rescue and rehabilitation centre, the park is the largest zoological garden in India.\nThe zoo houses 2,553 species of flora and fauna across 1,265 acres (512 ha).\nAs of 2012 the park houses around 1,500 wild species, including 46 endangered species, in its 160 enclosures</string>
    <string name="str_marina">Marina Beach is a natural urban beach in the city of Chennai, India, along the Bay of Bengal.The beach runs from near Fort St. George in the north to Foreshore Estate in the south, a distance of 6.5 km (4.0 mi),making it the longest natural urban beach in the country and the world\'s first longest natural urban beach.The Marina is primarily sandy, unlike the short, rocky formations that make up the Juhu Beach in Mumbai.\n The average width of the beach is 300 m (980 ft) and the width at the widest stretch is 437 m (1,434 ft).\nBathing and swimming at the Marina Beach are legally prohibited because of the dangers, as the undercurrent is very turbulent.\n It is one of the most crowded beaches in the country and attracts about 30,000 visitors a day during weekdays and 50,000 visitors a day during the weekends and on holiday</string>
    <string name="str_pulian">Puliyancholai is a scenic spot on the foothills of Kolli Hills. It is a forest region splashed with a small stream and covered with lush green foliage and tamarind groves. The place is a favorite haunt among the tourist throughout the year to enjoy bathing in natural springs. The Puliancholai falls is a terrace waterfall which appears like a stream of water that cascades through rocky terrain. Puliancholai is known for its scenic beauty located on the foot hills of kolli hills. It is a thick forest region, best suited for trekking and other adventurous activities. Located far away from the hustle and bustle of the urban areas, this place offers you a quite escape from busy city life. There is a Shiva Temple which is situated about 12 km inside the thick forest. Devotees come here to trek up to Shiva temple in June and July. Accommodation of provided by two resorts situated near the falls. The forests around this area have rich medical herbs. Pithukkuli Cave is another attraction nearby. The road access is available close to the waterfall and does not need much walking.</string>
    <string name="str_rock">Ucchi Pillayar koil, (Tamil: உச்சிப் பிள்ளையார் கோயில்) is a 7th-century Hindu temple, one dedicated to Lord Ganesh located a top of Rockfort, Trichy, Tamil Nadu, India. Mythologically this rock is the place where Lord Ganesh ran from King Vibishana, after establishing the Ranganathaswamy deity in Srirangam.\nThe Rock Fort temple stands 83m tall perched atop the rock. The smooth rock was first cut by the Pallavas but it was the Nayaks of Madurai who completed both the temples under the Vijayanagara empire.[1] The temple is situated at the top of the rock.The Ganesh temple is much smaller with an access through steep steps carved on the rock and provides a stunning view of Trichy, Srirangam and the rivers Kaveri and Kollidam. Due to its ancient and impressive architecture created by the Pallavas, the temple is maintained by the Archaeological department of India.</string>
    <string name="trichy">Trichy</string>
    <string name="chennai">Chennai</string>
    <string name="madurai">Madurai</string>
    <string name="coimbatore">Coimbatore</string>
    <string name="str_santh">San Thome Basilica is a Roman Catholic (Latin Rite) minor basilica in Santhome, in the city of Chennai (Madras), India.\n It was built in the 16th century by Portuguese explorers, over the tomb of St Thomas, an apostle of Jesus, after demolishing the original Kapaleeshwarar Temple which stood on the present site. In 1893, it was rebuilt as a church with the status of a cathedral by the British.\nThe British version still stands today. It was designed in Neo-Gothic style, favoured by British architects in the late 19th century.</string>
    <string name="txt_sr_description">Srirangam is famous for its Sri Ranganathaswamy Temple, a major pilgrimage destination for Hindus (especially Srivaishnavites) and the largest temple complex in India. According to the temple\'s website, Srirangam can be considered the biggest functioning Hindu temple in the world, as it covers an area of about 631,000 square metres (6,790,000 sq ft) with a perimeter of 4 km (10,710 ft).[1] Angkor Wat is bigger but non-functioning. Srirangam among a few shrines (Swayam Vyakta Kshetras) of Lord Vishnu. The temple is enormous in size. The temple complex is 156 acres (0.63 km2) in extent. It has seven prakaras or enclosures. These enclosures are formed by thick and huge rampart walls which run round the sanctum. There are 21 magnificent towers in all prakaras providing a unique sight to any visitor. The temple town lies on an islet formed by the twin rivers Cauvery and Coleroon. The Srirangam temple complex is composed of 7 concentric walled sections and 21 towers gopuram.The gopuram of the temple is called the Rajagopuram and is 236 feet (72 m) tall, the tallest in Asia.</string>
    <string name="str_kal_description">Kallanai (also known as the Grand Anicut) is an ancient dam, which is built (in running water) across the Kaveri River in Trichy District in the state of Tamil Nadu in South India.Located at a distance of 15 km from Tiruchirapalli, the dam was originally constructed by the Chola king Karikalan around the 2nd Century AD and is considered to be one of the oldest water-diversion or water-regulator structures in the world which is still in use.\nThe dam was originally built by Karikala Chola around second century AD.[4][5] The idea behind constructing the dam was to divert the river to the delta districts thereby boosting irrigation.[4] The dam was re-modeled by the British during the 19th century. In 1804, captain Caldwell, a military engineer was appointed by the British to make a study on the Kaveri river and promote irrigation for the delta region</string>
    <string name="txt_muk_description">The Upper Anaicut, (Tamil: மேலணை) also known as Mukkombu is a dam built on the Kaveri River in the state of Tamil Nadu in southern India. Upper Anaicut or Mukkombu is about 18 kilometers (11 mi) west of Trichy at a point where River Kollidam branches out from the main river, Cauvery. It is a lovely picnic spot skirting acres of verdant greenery. The place also has a well-manicured park. Mukkombu is about 685-meter long (2283 foot), and was built in the 19th century by Sir Arthur Cotton who drew inspiration from the 2nd century Kallanai dam (Grand Anicut) by the Cholas. The Kaveri river forms the boundary between the Erode and Salem districts. The Bhavani River joins the Kaveri at the town of Bhavani, where the Sangameswarar Temple, an important pilgrimage spot in Tamil Nadu, was built at the confluence of the two rivers. It breaks into two channels at the Upper Anaicut to form the island of Srirangam, which is enclosed in between the delta of Thanjavur (Tanjore), the garden of Tamil Nadu</string>
    <string name="str_connim">Connemara Public Library at Egmore in Chennai, Tamil Nadu, India, is one of the four National Depository Libraries which receive a copy of all books, newspapers and periodicals published in India. Established in 1890, the library is a repository of centuries-old publications, wherein lie some of the most respected works and collections in the country.\nIt also serves as a depository library for the UN.\nThe library, however, is not a registered member of the International Federation of Library Associations and Institutions</string>
</resources>
